[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla on today's episode we're looking
beyond the usual coding assistance we've
already talked a little bit about
various code suggestions and things like
that that these tools offer Us in line
as we code in our IDE there are also a
number of other ways in which we can use
AI to generate code for us through
natural language uh in a more automated
way and we're going to look at a range
of options all the way up to defining
components as specifications as well my
name is Simon Maple I'm the host for the
episode and joining me today is Devin
Stein founder of dosu Welcome to the
podcast episode Devon how are you I'm
doing well thanks for having me Simon
awesome it's a pleasure and why don't we
actually before we jump in I know you've
been a software engineer at various
places before Jo before founding Dosey
tell us a little bit about about what
dosu is and a little bit about your
background as well yeah for a quick
background I've been early engineer at
par startups most recently had an ml
startup called viaduct in the automotive
space so different from what we do today
but a lot of parallels as we'll dive
into and about a year just over a year
ago started dosu and at dosu we're
really focused on all the work helping
automate the work Engineers do outside
of the IDE so taking things off
Engineers plate so they can actually
focus on coding whether that's answering
questions so they don't they are
interrupted helping take a first pass on
issue triage or helping them maintain
documentation are all the types of
things that we're focused on at
dosu yeah amazing and so when we think
about the type of interaction AI needs
to have in these various forms so
obviously in an IDE it needs to be an a
coding assistant right it's a line
forline coding assistant what kind of
differences do you feel feel a user need
or developer needs to have in the
various places so we have the IDE maybe
there's other things like various
tickets or pool requests how have you
found the need of that interaction style
to be different yeah I think the main
difference is a lot of the tasks that we
focus on at dosu and the things that
happen outside of the IDE are more
asynchronous so you have more time when
you have something like hit up copilot
in the IDE people speed really matters
you want to be super Snappy but the
problem space I we're focused on is like
how do we stop Engineers from being
interrupted essentially and you think
about like when you get interrupted it's
like getting pinged in slack about a
question or on a new ticket in jira that
some customers have an issue that you
have to leave what you're doing and look
into and so with those tickets the kind
of Delta between getting pinged and
responding could be minutes and so you
actually have a lot more time in the
background to make sure you're Gathering
the right context and then providing a
valuable information back to end users
so it's a slightly different interaction
pattern yeah yeah and it's quite
interesting actually because with that
additional time that you have it's it's
it's almost like you don't you want to
be wrong Less in the sense because when
the speed matters so much in a code
completion point of view I guess there's
always a balance between time and
accuracy and with in a code completion
point of view it's important that the
code suggestions are happening at the
time that a developer is thinking and
wanting to act whereas with these PR s
and and tickets and things like that
like you say when you have a few minutes
you still you want to be super accurate
at that point you want to actually do
something that is is truly what a
developer wants to
do without causing more work for that
developer is that something that you've
played with more or able to do a greater
number of things because you have that
less of that time restraint yeah I think
that's actually spoton and something we
hear from users consistently is when
you're working in this kind of
asynchronous more work domain precis
really matters you rather deliver one
good response or than five average
responses and that's part of the reason
with dosu our product strategy has
always been been very public and we've
launched really early and part of that
is trying to understand all the types of
request developers get and figuring out
what we call internally like a
confidence threshold like when does it
make sense for dosu to respond when does
it think it has a good answer or
relevant context the because like you're
saying is like delivering incorrect
information you maybe caused more work
versus not responding it's status quo
but if you deliver high quality
information good response then you
actually save a ton of time being
careful about when we respond is
something that we've been getting better
at but there's still a ton of work to do
and I think generally in the llm space
there isn't as much discussion about
robustness thinking like when should
llms respond versus I think right now
they have a bias towards all always
responding and saying yes um very
positive they will do what you ask them
to do because that's how they're trained
and so there's a bit of like some on the
modeling side but also on the product
side trying to unwind some of
that yeah absolutely it's yeah it's real
thing I'm not wanting to say no at times
to your requests and I've been playing a
little bit with with AI through content
generation and things like that and it's
funny when I ask it to do things like oh
yeah scale this the Tesla website to see
if there are other blogs and and
podcasts and things like that have
similar themes or content that we can
link to as a as a kind of like useful
thing so that it's an automated thing
that I don't have to then go away and do
and it's interesting because if it
doesn't find something it'll make up
content that doesn't exist and it will
say oh yeah I've even created the title
and the link to it and things like that
so it's a real problem in in not wanting
to say to say no is this something that
you have to add into the kind of like
the system prompts and things like that
to be able to make it more accurate
based on things that are absolutely true
versus what it wants to be true yes we
basically spend a lot of time trying to
gather context and make sure that the
final context that we show do before it
responds is high quality and if we can't
find kind of high quality context then
it will respond saying that it couldn't
find any relevant information maybe
prompt the user for information I think
there is still and something that we're
so working on is still like a bias
towards llms want to jump into solution
space it might find out that the answer
isn't possible like what the user is
asking for isn't possible but then it'll
be like oh you could also try this other
thing but the correct answer is this
isn't possible but LM will tend to try
push towards you could maybe do this
instead we definitely have to and have
been building like guard rails around
that as well and then generally output
filtering hallucination checks is very
important in this
space yeah no absolutely I think those
filters are extremely important I I want
to switch back to to something that you
mentioned earlier all around context and
I guess you know for a couple of
different ways in which we might want to
develop an application some might be it
might be a first of all an application
that's been created from scratch a new
component or something like that very
little context versus an an existing
application a large application that
we're trying to make changes to what are
the advantages and disadvantages of each
approach from the users's point of view
or from the lm's point of view in terms
of whether it can be more accurate more
timely in responses those kind of things
it's a good question I'll speak to my
experience both at dosu and personally
just using llms and AI as a developer I
so at dosu we're very focused on L large
code bases that's where the maintenance
burden of code kind of increases with
size and complexity of code Base number
of people working on it but personally I
always use llms for kind of that zero to
one generation I think llms are are
really good at writing code and writing
like scripts and so if you want some a
web page to do something or a script to
help you automate some sort of part of
your workflow I think they're very good
at that because they can rely on the
pre-training like what they already know
and don't have to worry about what is
the appropriate dependency to use or is
this code in the right style or maybe
this function is already implemented
somewhere in this code base and they
should import it instead of rewriting it
um so I think LMS Thrive at that and
then when you put them in a larger code
base um part of the challenge is that
context of making sure that any code you
generate is in the correct style it's
using the libraries and the versions
that code base uses or it's following
best practices or some like most
codebase have some weird patterns that
some engineer early on started enforcing
and you need to follow because generally
kind of standardization is important
that scale and then so that's one part
is like understanding kind of how the
code should be written or where it lives
and then for us at dosu were work in
this space where you know often outside
of the IDE where people are not talking
about code in a code sense so when
people raise issues or questions to dosu
they're often describing things in
product language you know how how do we
handle this scenario in this product
feature there's no mention of a class
name or a file name and so a lot of the
work we have to do is figure out how do
we generate a map of like product level
Concepts back to engineering World which
is like code files functions Etc and I
think that is really important when you
think about llms for like larger code
bases because product is just how people
talk about development at scale they
don't really get too In The Weeds on
like function names they're saying I
want to change this feature I want to
understand why this is happening with
this product
future yeah that's really interesting
and I there's there's a few things that
I'd love to break down so so one of the
things I loved that you mentioned was
about the developer style and I think
yeah developer style is one of those
things where you often see probably more
I would say probably more experienced or
more senior developers who are more
attached to the style of either their
code or the components code that that
they're working on in terms of obviously
with a smaller project or project from
scratch it's extremely hard unless
you're unless the the tool or
application that you are using to to
help generate this suggested code knows
you as an individual knows you as a user
it it doesn't necessarily have a code
base to go from how accurate can the llm
be in terms of providing suggestions in
the style of the existing code base is
that good enough today do you think or
do you feel like we've got further to go
I don't think it's a clear clear cut
answer I think part of the challenge
with llms is that you have to describe
what you want often and describing the
style of codebase it's really hard some
codebases have really written style
guides and in those scenarios it's
possible that I could see an llm being
able to generate code or an edit in that
style but even within a very detailed
style guide there's probably subtleties
around we actually have all utility
functions stored in this um part of the
mono repo um or if we're going to define
a new service we want to make sure it's
uses FS this naming pattern and we
create a new directory I think it's
really hard to capture all those
subtleties but I think if you give an LM
a very comprehensive description it can
do a pretty solid job even in today's
world I think where you see I saw I read
you recently Google put out a blog post
paper on how they do have been using
llms for code migrations and I think a
very common pattern in where we seeing
llms Excel and something we've been
leaning to at dosu is using examples so
showing examples of like here this is
the type of style that I want and having
a few different ex variations of that I
think LMS are really good at learning
kind of implicit styles through examples
so I think there's something there
around if you can maybe learn or find
examples of this developer code in the
past I think elm's might actually be
able to learn that developer style
almost implicitly rather than the
explicit style guide
approach yeah very interesting and I
think one other area actually when we
think about when we think about existing
code bases like that large repos that
maybe monor repos or whatever it is if I
was a front-end developer or if I was a
backend developer
I'm writing some code and I need it to
be able to connect to the front end or
the back end vice versa how good is it
today at do you feel if I'm writing some
front-end code being able to connect
those requests into the the correct
backend pieces is it good enough to pick
out the right backend calls that need to
be made or is there still a a context
problem then definitely a bit of a
context problem I think this going back
to what I was saying before on the
product side and I think I think
thinking about things from a product
perspective actually forms really
natural grouping between these District
parts of codebases so front end backend
you might be looking at and I'm thinking
in dosu world but like a list of data
sources so there is a page on our web
app that has that and then there's
backend code around data sources and how
we process and store those and so
connecting those two as like the data
source places where you look when you're
working with data sources I think is how
you can create a mapping between these
dist parts of the codebase and
I think it gets even harder when at most
companies they're not all monor repos so
you're talking about multi- repositories
and so trying to figure out okay given
this feature which repositories do I
need to change and then which files
within those repositories figuring that
out is challenging and I think it comes
down to it's a context problem so
figuring out how to break down the
request into and find the relevant
pieces of the codebase and it's hard but
think I really think that there's a lot
of potential and Power in thinking
things from like a product first
perspective and the same way you as a
developer yeah and I guess two things so
I'd love to dig a little bit deeper into
the kind of like describing things as
product features versus code I think one
thing maybe even before that as well is
in order to break the existing code base
down or many repos there's almost
somewhat it feels like the lln needs to
recognize and understand the
architecture that exists so that it can
almost understand understand the user
flows or the product flows going through
so it it recognizes okay if a user
request has this path it needs to touch
the front end it needs to go grab some
data Maybe pass that data back in a
certain format to the front end which
displays it like this it it really needs
to understand that and I think this is
almost the style at which a user maybe
wants to map a request into an llm in
terms of being able to say this is what
I want from that from this
new new use case to be designed how good
do you feel from your experience with
dosu are developers
at describing with enough detail but not
too much context almost these kinds of
requests I think so on the architecture
point I think that's a really it's a
good one I think it's the same type of
what are abstractions that we can give
llms in order for them to understand the
tendencies that are more complex so I
think looking at it from a product angle
is one I think from an architecture
perspective also helps llms understand
those dependencies from what we've seen
llms are not at that strong and their
current form of reasoning about higher
level architecture and like the
implications of that I can speak about
our own is fair async Pub sub like a
vent driven and llms definitely struggle
with reasoning about exactly once
delivery and item potency and the
implications of that but I think going
to describing all of that to the llm I
think that is
the LMS are not magic they are as good
as the inputs and we find that
developers it can be it's a lot to
describe if you think about your look at
any companies like backlog the tickets
are typically pretty sparse because
there's a lot of implicit context and
it's a lot of work to write things out
in detail so one thing that I think dosu
does well and LMS can help with is this
kind of context Gathering where hey you
keep it high level dosu finds relevant
resources that it thinks hey you're
talking about these types of files here
are some related PRS and some
documentation I found and then can
actually use that to maybe flush out the
description more and I think that kind
of helps with this back and forth and
we've been seeing that in a lot of AI
developer type products where there's a
it's a human in the loop experience
where llms are gathering context for you
you're saying like yes that is what I
want or no look for XYZ instead so I
think one shot developers describing
exactly what they want I don't think
they're generally that good at it just
cuz it's a lot of
work yeah yeah no absolutely and I think
it's not something that developers are
naturally have had to do to someone who
isn't going to discuss with them like a
human or someone like that in terms of
what an llm is good at and and still
needs help with today we mentioned
existing code bases that an LM has to
troll through in order to be able to
understand and and make changes versus
Greenfield projects it's probably fair
to say they're going to be better at New
Creation than performing changes to
existing file or existing codebases
correctly because there is so much
relevant context in an existing code
base if they don't do that correct or
that rather there are many ways in which
they can get it wrong one fewer ways
that they can get it right with existing
so much existing context is that fair I
think that's very fair and I think
there's two parts of that one on just
the model level just where we are at
technology wise llms are notoriously bad
at patch generation so actually making
an edit to a file the often the best way
to do that right now is just rewrite
files and that doesn't scale and in
terms of there are very large files out
there and I think that is a solvable
problem I think patches just happen to
be very out of distribution in the way
that models are trained but it's almost
guaranteed in the next I don't know year
maybe even less there's going to be a
model that is very good at past
generation so I think on the modeling
side that will get better over time and
then like you're saying when you have a
very large code base it means you're
making many edits typically especially
for any significant Feature work and
whenever Elms are probabilistic if you
make a thousand edits to a code base and
there's this very small error percentage
you're going to get things wrong and so
the more places you have to change the
more likelihood there is error as well
so that's another challenge with larger
code bases that you don't get in that 0
to one and what is it about the patch
that makes it specifically that much
harder than the complete file rerun it's
the just uh like the way you look at a
patch like it's not very like anything
else really like it's has a very
specific kind of do it's a domain
specific language um and so LMS that are
trained on just code and just text can
come up with pches but there is a strict
schema requirement for it and and
there's a lot of ways that it can be
wrong it's not the most intuitive format
I don't know if you've ever looked at
like a patch file and it's pluses add
this file delete this file and you have
to be able to reason about that patch
within the context of a larger file as
well so it's um it's it's basically a
domain specific language and right now
llms at least out of the box aren't
super reliable with that patch
format yeah and and and what else is
still need what what are the areas of an
llm do we still need it to improve in in
order for a general experience through
through development to be better with AI
so I think there are like endless things
that experiments and ideas I want to
explore about ways you know we can make
LMS better at navigating code bases but
one thing that we have been really
focused on and I alluded to a bit before
at dosu that I think is important is
when people talk about llms or AI
software developers or agents more
generally they often compare them to
employees right we're building an AI
software engineer we're building a AI
sales development rep or AI executive
assistant and I think that analogies is
actually really apt because when you
hire someone as let's say a software
engineer you don't expect them to come
in and read your entire code base and
then just know what to do what you do is
you expect them to read it try get a
sense of what's going on try tackle a
ticket or and either one make mistakes
and then be corrected say on a PR or
just in a conversation or ask questions
hey I'm trying to do this but I don't
really understand this or should I do
this should I do a or b and then get a
new answer and then over time through
these Corrections and answers you expect
them to become more and more proficient
and that's something we're really trying
to lean into on with dosu is how do we
do is going to make mistakes like llms
will make mistakes but how do we learn
from that get feedback and then uh make
sure they don't make the same mistake
twice so then over time as you invest in
the product and as it sees more and more
examples it gets better and can achieve
a level of proficiency that you would
expect of kind of an
employee yeah yeah absolutely and when
we think about when we think about the
way we
are currently describing things that we
want to change code changes and so forth
how do we need to think about how we
describe code changes to an
llm that's yeah so the way it's done
today you know is often I think people
have aligned on this kind of subtask
like problem breakdown approach so you
describe this higher level problem the
llm tries to come up with a plan or
break it down into smaller pieces and
then it tries to execute on that plan in
like smaller kind of components one at a
time and then synthesize the
results this is we follow something very
similar to this at dosu and the
challenges with that is there's a lot of
steps where it can go wrong if you break
something down to a 12-step plan there
are like those sub plans might then be
broken down further and again going back
to LMS they probabilistic like the more
times you're making a call or a change
there's a higher likelihood of failure
and you often need humans in the loop
what we've seen is you have someone
checking the plan or watching its
progress making sure it's okay and then
similarly if you the plan is too vague
which actually is something we see a lot
in production is people like we're
saying UND specify so if things are
vague it'll often try find more context
that isn't relevant to the problem if
you're not specific enough and more
context can confuse llms as well and so
that's how it's done today and then
looking forward I think with all things
in software engineering I think we need
better abstractions and better
Primitives where llms are not having to
think in such small granular detail so
that it's able to make larger sweeping
changes more reliably than what exists
today yeah and you mentioned a little
bit there about too much context almost
how do you at those two identify what
the right amount of context is so the
way we approach it again specific to our
asynchronous use case where we have a
bit more time but it is basically often
times we found that there's a
correlation between the amount of tokens
in and the like length of the output you
get and sometimes the answer to a
complex question could be just one or
two sentences and something so that
conciseness something we've been working
on a lot but at a high level the way we
approach the too much Contex thing is we
spend the time basically you can think
of it refining the context so like a
thinking almost like a sculptor but
really chisling away at this larger
block of context to only the pieces that
we believe are relevant to this problem
and the final prompt we crafting is
ideally very high quality with only the
specific information so we just take
some time to refine the larger inputs
into a smaller higher quality
informationally dense prompt at the
end yeah interesting because I think
that's one of the biggest kind of like
problems today I think is we recognize
that context is is so valuable in terms
of of providing a far better answer but
we're still having problems in terms of
determining what the right level of
context and I think it's a lot of it is
US learning what we need to provide
we're going to look to the Future a
little bit just to wrap this up but
before we do we're going to try
something new actually on the podcast
which is we're going to do a we're going
to do a share the screen piece which
we're going to going to wrap up in as a
separate episode which is going to
follow this D immediately in terms of
before we jump to the Future what are
the kind of things that we can look
forward to seeing in that in that next
episode that you're going to show us
you're going to show us it through Dosey
but we want to really talk about a lot
of the a lot of the technologies that
we've that we've talked about yeah I
guess didn't get too much into dosu but
dosu is extremely popular right now
within open source helping open source
maintainers support and grow their
Community with with maintenance and so
dos is installed on thousands of
repositories and open source is public
and so there's a lot of pretty cool
examples of dosu doing really well
providing a ton of value to developers
and also helping showcase where LMS fall
short and where there is room for
improvement so I think it would be
useful to walk through some examples of
noou doing helping developers out based
off the context of the code base
answering questions that would not be
well documented but the answer does live
in a code base and that's something
that's important to us is like treating
code is a source of Truth like a
developer does and other examples of
dosu autonomously resolving issues with
a combination of code and documentation
and then also ones where it can it gets
to a solution but it isn't the optimal
solution tying it back to what we were
saying before of like LMS want to give
you uh a solution when the solution
might be there is no
solution yes absolutely excellent so
yeah for those who are listening that's
uh follow straight after so just skip to
the next episode and you'll see that
obviously best with video this one uh as
uh as we're going to be doing a fair bit
of screen sharing so yeah look into the
future just to wrap this this episode up
look to the Future we're talking about
and particularly when we're talking
about making changes or creating new
code through prompts and even when we
elevated it that little bit up where
we're trying to get users effectively to
talk not through code but actually
through use cases almost so talk to me
via product word and and we'll turn that
into code what where is this leading us
what's the what's the kind of future of
this a few steps a few years down the
line what what do you foresee is the the
interaction between developers and the
some backend that will generate Cod for
yeah I'll I'll cave out everything I say
in that it's very hard to predict the
future right now things are moving very
fast my God particularly in AI yes I
think yeah the this rate of change has
been incredible it's really hard to
predict like how things will evolve but
I think something that has been true for
many years now is that as software
development has progressed the level of
abstraction has also increased and I'm
my take I'm like a pretty firm believer
for llms to or AI to become actually
building apps for us similar to how what
we expect from software Engineers I
think that code itself as it exists
today isn't necessarily the right
abstraction if you think about basically
like programming languages like we were
saying before there's to implement a
feature or to modify behavior requires a
lot of changes and this like the level
of abstraction within programming
languages hasn't really changed that
much in the past 10 20 years we have new
languages like rust python is still I
would say one of the more abstract and
like higher level programming languages
and it also happens to be what LMS are
very good at but I think in order for
llms to become more proficient at
building apps the way we expect software
Engineers to we need like abstractions
around what apps are that llms can think
in and modify and so the one that top of
mind one that comes is really like rest
apis I think there's a lot of work that
has been done around rest apis and code
generation but it feels like something
that is such a key concept or like core
primitive to Modern web apps that you
could imagine like a language or spec or
yeah like some abstraction around rest
API or restful services that allow llms
to operate in that domain they're not
worrying about kind of the Implement
implementation details of that rest API
they're thinking about what types of
filters do we need to support what is
the input output and then there are
tools to compile that into maybe it's
python or code under the hood but I
think thinking about having higher level
Primitives that LMS can think about and
not worry too much about the low level
quotequote lowlevel code that we use
today yeah and it's really so I love the
idea actually starting from the rest API
or any API in particular because it
allows people to think about the usage
of that component the use cases and and
the flows that you'd like to make um
python so interestingly you went you
talked about a python like language is
that there's too much ambiguity almost
through through the English language or
you feel like it needs to be styled in a
specific way so you use more kind of
like a DSL like python notation yeah so
I mentioned python because I think
Python's a good example of a higher
level programming language today that
has helped developers be more productive
without worrying about too much of the
details under the hood I think for I
think there's some people believe like
English is the future of code I would be
concerned with that I think with code
and you all you need code because it
helps you be specific and so I think
whatever this abstraction and that is
like the challenge with abstractions is
finding what is the level of specificity
that we actually need for llms to do
their job effectively that is the key
Challenge and I think rest apis is just
an easy example where there isn't that
much like surface area if you were to
create some sort of Attraction DSL
there's a lot of already opening open
API specs and code generation around it
where you can think about things in
terms of input output and like kind of
parameters and you can generate a lot of
code from that yeah no love it love it
and what what does a developer look like
then in that case if they're if they're
more on the specification angle what's
the role of a Dev I don't think
developers are going away but I think
the developers will be more productive
and expected to do more and it also I
think lowers the bar for developers
similar honestly to python you try
program and c and there's a pretty high
bar entry you're going to be running to
a lot of errors that are hard to be
debug and reason about but python makes
it a lot easier for people to write
scripts who maybe are self-taught and I
think the same thing will happen within
llms especially for creating more simple
CR apps or you will have people that are
able to maybe non-engineers or engineer
related roles like like PMS designers
Etc that are able to spin up web apps
for side projects for internal tools
that sort of thing and then similarly on
the kind of developer developer I think
yeah they'll just be more
productive yeah amazing well that's a
great that's a great that's a great
point to end the episode I feel it's
it's a very positive looking angle in
terms of what the what developers have
to look forward to and also how it
broadens that role Devin thank you so
much I really appreciate your sites and
looking forward to jumping in next to
actually get our hands dirty a little
bit and actually see some of this in
action so Devon thanks very much and
looking forward to the next session
thank you s t of
[Applause]
fun thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
oh